- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦 ♪
- Hey, Dad? Remember how mad you were
嘿，爸爸？记得你当时有多生气吗？
when the dog groomers next door
当隔壁的狗狗美容师
dumped all their old dog hair in our dumpster?
把他们所有的旧狗毛都倒进我们的垃圾桶时？
- Those hair-dumping Montagellis.
那些倒狗毛的蒙塔杰利斯。
- And remember how when they went on vacation
还记得他们去度假时
we got revenge by shoving tuna salad in their mail slot?
我们是如何通过把金枪鱼沙拉塞进他们的邮箱来报复的吗？
- Those tuna-salad-stinking Montagellis.
那些金枪鱼沙拉臭气熏天的蒙塔杰利斯。
- And remember how you said you'd flip out
还记得你说过如果蒙塔杰利斯再进来这里，你会发疯的吗？
if the Montagellis ever came in here again?
那些再进来的蒙塔杰利斯！
[eerie suspenseful music]
- Those come-in-here-again Montagellis!
- 那些再次闯进来的蒙塔杰利斯！
Ah!
啊！
- He did say he'd flip out. - He's a man of his word.
- 他的确说过他会发疯。 - 他是言出必行的人。
- Anne! The Montagellis are here!
- 安妮！蒙塔杰利斯在这里！
- I knew it was Monta-smelly in here.
- 我就知道这里有蒙塔臭味。
- What're you doing here, Monta-smellies?
- 你们在这里做什么，蒙塔臭们？
- Yeah, you know the rules.
- 是的，你们知道规矩。
We're banned from the groomers,
我们被禁止进入美容院，
and you're banned from Get Sporty.
而你们被禁止进入Get Sporty。
- Look, we're only here because my dad wanted
- 看，我们只是因为爸爸想
to make sure you guys got a package
确保你们能拿到一个包裹
the mailman accidentally left with us.
邮递员不小心留在了我们那里。
- Oh, well, thank you.
- 哦，那谢谢了。
[glass shatters] Ah!
[玻璃破碎声] 啊！
- Mom, didn't the mailman leave a package here
- 妈妈，邮递员不是留了一个包裹在这里
for the Montagellis? - Yes, he did.
给蒙塔杰利家的吗？ - 是的，他留了。
Thank you for reminding me.
谢谢你提醒我。
[glass shatters] - Ah!
[玻璃破碎声] - 啊！
- We loathe you, Harpers!
- 我们讨厌你们，哈珀家！
- We loathe you, Montagellis!
我们讨厌你们，蒙塔杰利斯！
- Maybe you guys should loathe the mailman.
也许你们应该讨厌邮递员。
He's clearly not very good at his job.
他显然不太擅长他的工作。
- Beat it, Monta-smellies.
滚开，蒙塔-臭利斯。
- Don't worry. No Montagelli would ever be
别担心。没有一个蒙塔杰利会靠近哈-普尔家族。
anywhere near a Har-pooper.
那么你认为我们什么时候可以告诉我们的家人彼此的事情？
So when do you think we can tell our families about each other?
哦，你知道的，永远不会。
- Oh, you know, never.
[欢快音乐]
[upbeat music]
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
- ♪ ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- Hey, do you guys wanna go door-to-door asking for money?
- 嘿，你们想不想挨家挨户去要钱？
- I'm in. - Yep.
- 我加入。 - 是的。
I like money. - You don't get to keep it.
我喜欢钱。 - 你不能留着它。
- I'm out. - Nope.
- 我不干了。 - 不行。
- Always a catch. - Come on.
- 总是有条件的。 - 拜托。
Our Nature Club is raising money for Charity.
我们的自然俱乐部正在为慈善筹款。
She's an injured, flightless goose
她是一只受伤的、无法飞行的鹅
living in the alley behind Get Sporty.
住在Get Sporty后面的巷子里。
- So your charity is for Charity?
- 所以你的慈善是为了Charity？
- A little on the nose, don't you think?
- 有点太直白了，你不觉得吗？
- The money we raise will help ship the goose
- 我们筹集的资金将帮助把这只鹅
back to her gaggle in Canada.
送回她在加拿大的鹅群。
- Yeah, how have you guys not heard about this?
- 是啊，你们怎么还没听说过这件事？
It's a huge story all over the Internet.
这在网上是个大新闻。
- Um, maybe because we don't care about some dumb bird.
- 呃，可能是因为我们不在乎那只笨鸟。
- Get that bird!
抓住那只鸟！
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
[electronic game sounds]
[电子游戏声音]
all: Hey!
嘿！
[romantic music]
[浪漫音乐]
♪ ♪
[together] Hello.
一起说：你好。
- These are my friends from Nature Club.
这些是我的自然俱乐部的朋友。
Faith, Hope, and Susan.
Faith, Hope, 和 Susan。
- So you guys are gonna help us raise money for Charity?
所以你们会帮我们为慈善筹款吗？
- That poor, flightless bird
- 那只可怜的、不会飞的鸟
living in the alley behind Get Sporty?
住在Get Sporty后面小巷里的？
- Of course we're going to help you.
- 当然我们会帮助你。
- Yeah, it's a huge story. It's all over the Internet.
- 是的，这是一个大新闻。网上到处都是。
- Come on, girls.
- 来吧，女孩们。
Help me set up these collection boxes.
帮我设置这些募捐箱。
- You guys don't care about Charity.
- 你们这些人根本不在乎慈善。
- [gasps] - How dare you, Dawn.
- [倒吸一口气] - 你怎么敢这么说，Dawn。
We love that duck. - Duck?
我们爱那只鸭子。 - 鸭子？
- Goose. - both: Right.
- 鹅。 - 都对。
- You just wanna impress those girls.
- 你只是想给那些女孩留下好印象。
- "Impress" those girls? Please.
- 给那些女孩留下好印象？拜托。
I know how we can impress those girls.
我知道我们怎样能给那些女孩留下好印象。
You know, instead of begging for money door-to-door,
你知道，与其挨家挨户乞讨，
why don't we do something classier?
我们为什么不做得更优雅一些？
Like begging for money online. - Ah, good one.
比如在网上乞讨。 - 啊，好主意。
- I guess there are some websites
- 我想有些网站
where you could post videos to raise money for a charity.
你可以在那里发布视频为慈善筹款。
- Oh, we could make a funny comedy video with the goose
- 哦，我们可以和那只鹅一起制作一个搞笑喜剧视频
to ask for money. - That could work.
来请求捐款。 - 那可能行得通。
- Totally could. - Oh please.
- 完全可能。 - 哦，拜托。
There's nothing worse than guys trying to be funny online.
没有什么比在网上试图搞笑的家伙更糟糕的了。
- Yeah. - Of course.
- 是啊。 - 当然。
- Yeah, bad idea, Dawn.
- 是啊，坏主意，Dawn。
- Why don't we do a benefit at the cafe?
- 我们为什么不在咖啡馆办个慈善活动呢？
We could get a bunch of performers to do a show
我们可以邀请很多表演者来演出
and we'd charge admission.
并且收取入场费。
- Yeah, but we'd just need to find performers.
- 是的，但我们只需要找到表演者。
- We could perform. Right, boys?
- 我们可以自己表演。对吧，伙计们？
- Yeah. - That could be great.
- 是的。 - 那可能会很棒。
- I'm willing to try it. - Oh, please.
- 我愿意试试。 - 哦，拜托。
There's nothing worse than guys trying to sing when they can't.
没有什么比那些不会唱歌却硬要唱的男生更糟糕的了。
both: Yep. - Another stinker, Dawn.
两人: 没错。 - 又是一个糟糕的主意，Dawn。
- But the benefit show is a good idea.
- 但慈善演出是个好主意。
- Excellent.
- 太好了。
So why don't we get away from Dawn
那我们为什么不离开Dawn
and her terrible ideas
和她那些糟糕的主意
and discuss this over some delicious cookies?
然后边吃美味的饼干边讨论这个呢？
- Yeah, I have some ginger snaps cooling on the counter.
- 是的，我有些姜饼正在柜台上冷却。
[cell phone dings]
[手机叮了一声]
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- Dawn, are you texting with a boy?
- Dawn，你在和男生发短信吗？
- No. [cell phone dings]
- 不是。[手机叮了一声]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- I know that giggle.
- 我知道那种笑声。
You are totally texting with a boy.
你绝对是在和男生发短信。
- No, I'm not.
- 我没有。
[cell phone dings] - Fine.
[手机叮了一声] - 好吧。
Then look at that next text without smiling or giggling.
那么，在不笑或咯咯笑的情况下看下一条短信。
- Piece of cake.
- 小菜一碟。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Dang it.
该死。
- Okay, Dawn, spill it.
- 好吧，Dawn，快说。
- Fine, but you can't tell anybody, okay?
- 好吧，但你不能告诉任何人，好吗？
So a few weeks ago, I was taking the trash out to the dumpster,
所以几周前，我正把垃圾拿到垃圾箱去，
and saying hi to Charity. [goose honks]
并向Charity打招呼。[鹅叫]
When I heard...
这时我听到...
[acoustic guitar music playing]
[原声吉他音乐播放]
- ♪ Everybody gets by sometimes you know ♪
- ♪ 每个人有时都会过得去，你知道的 ♪
♪ ♪
♪ What else can we do when we're feelin' low ♪
♪当我们感到低落时，我们还能做些什么呢♪
- Why is such a great musician playing out here in the alley?
为什么这么伟大的音乐家会在小巷里演奏？
- I like the acoustics.
我喜欢这里的音响效果。
Why is such a cute girl taking out the trash?
为什么这么可爱的女孩在倒垃圾？
- I like the scenery.
我喜欢这里的风景。
- It's even better from where I'm standing.
从我站的地方看更好。
- And we've been hanging out ever since.
从那以后我们就一直在一起。
- Ooh, a secret romance with an older boy,
哦，和一个年长的男孩的秘密恋情，
and between feuding families too.
而且还是在有纷争的家庭之间。
- I know but that's why
我知道，这就是为什么
we haven't told anybody about us yet.
我们还没告诉任何人我们的事。
- You guys are like Romeo and Juliet.
你们就像罗密欧与朱丽叶。
Joey-o and Dawn-iet.
乔伊-欧和丹-欧。
Dawn-eo and Joey-et.
丹-欧和乔伊-欧。
[laughs] JoJo and Big D.
[笑] 乔乔和大D。
I'll work on it.
我会琢磨琢磨的。
[rock music]
[摇滚音乐]
- Thanks again for letting us hold the auditions in the cafe.
再次感谢你让我们在咖啡馆举行试镜。
- Oh, honey, we're happy to let you use the cafe
哦，亲爱的，我们很高兴让你用咖啡馆
for such a good cause. - Absolutely.
为了这么好的事业。 - 绝对没问题。
We're all about charity. [chuckles]
我们都是为了慈善。[轻笑]
Try to get people to eat. Push the egg salad.
尽量让人们多吃点。推一下鸡蛋沙拉。
It's just on the verge.
就在边缘。
- Uh, before we get started,
- 呃，在我们开始之前，
can I interest anyone in an egg salad sandwich?
有人对鸡蛋沙拉三明治感兴趣吗？
- Ooh, I'm interested.
- 哦，我有兴趣。
- Oh, uh...
- 哦，呃...
Dad said it's on the verge.
爸爸说它在边缘。
- Ah, usually I have it on wheat,
- 啊，通常我会在小麦面包上吃，
but let's mix it up.
但让我们换个花样。
- Uh, one egg salad sandwich.
嗯，一个鸡蛋沙拉三明治。
- Ooh, on verge.
哦，边缘的。
- First up is Natlee
首先上场的是Natlee
and Old-Schooley Dooley.
和Old-Schooley Dooley。
- Today, I'm gonna be poppin' and lockin' for ya.
今天，我要为你们表演 popping 和 locking。
- Oh, no.
哦，不。
- Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
[funky electronic music playing on radio]
[电子音乐在收音机上播放]
- Here we go.
开始了。
- Come on.
来吧。
- I like where this is going.
我喜欢这个发展方向。
- I have a good feeling about this.
我对这个感觉不错。
- They're wasting our lives right now.
他们现在正在浪费我们的生命。
- Aww, yeah.
啊，没错。
- Aww--no.
啊，不。
- Yeah, they really stunk up the joint.
是啊，他们真的搞砸了。
- Yeah, it's all roses from here on out.
是啊，从现在开始一切都会很美好。
- Definitely.
当然。
- Ah, this smells worse than Dooley.
啊，这味道比杜利还难闻。
- Knock, knock.
敲敲门。
Knock, knock.
[falsetto] Who's there?
[假声]谁在那儿？
- Not you.
- 不是你。
[dramatic Latin music]
[戏剧性的拉丁音乐]
♪ ♪
both: Olé!
两人: 奥莱！
- Oh, my.
- 哦，我的天。
- Oh, boys. - Oh, no.
- 哦，男孩们。 - 哦，不。
- How are we ever gonna find a performer
- 我们怎么才能找到一个表演者
that will raise enough money to impress the girls?
- 能筹集足够资金来打动女孩们？
- Oh, and help Charity. - Oh, come on.
We all know you're only doing it for the girls.
[all gasp] - Please.
You lie worse than Dooley break dances.
- Hey, can you take the trash out to the dumpster?
I think I pulled a glute doing all those puntas y plantas.
- Fine. - Sure.
- Ugh, my stomach hurts.
- Look, I know you don't want anyone
to know about you and Joey,
but maybe we should ask him to sing at the benefit.
但是，也许我们应该请他在慈善活动中唱歌。
You said he was really good.
你说过他唱得真的很好。
- It's too risky for us to be together in public.
- 对我们来说，在公共场合一起出现太冒险了。
- Just act like you don't like each other.
- 就假装你们彼此不喜欢。
- [scoffs] Yeah, right.
- [嗤之以鼻] 是啊，没错。
Whenever Joey and I are together,
每当乔伊和我在一起时，
we can't help but make goo-goo eyes at each other.
我们忍不住要互相眉来眼去。
- Well, you better find a way for that goo-goo to go-go
- 好吧，你们最好找个办法让这种眉目传情消失
'cause Jo-Jo just walked in the do-do.
因为乔-乔刚刚走进了这里。
- We found our star act for the benefit!
- 我们找到了慈善活动的明星表演！
- Yeah, he was singing in the alley to some bird.
是的，他在小巷里对着一只鸟唱歌。
- He's a filthy Montagelli, but...
他是个肮脏的蒙塔格内利，但是...
he's got the voice of an angel.
他有着天使般的嗓音。
- This is not good. - No, this is terrible.
这不太好。
But kind of wonderful.
不，这很糟糕。
But terrible. But...
但有点美妙。
kinda wonderful.
但很糟糕。但...
Terrible. But wonderful.
有点美妙。
- Thank you. It's terrible.
糟糕。但美妙。
♪♪
谢谢。这很糟糕。
[rock music]
♪摇滚音乐♪
- What are you guys doing? Joey is not allowed--
- 你们在干什么？Joey是不允许——
I mean, this stinky,
- 我是说，这个臭烘烘的、
low-rent pet barber isn't allowed in here.
- 低档宠物美容师是不允许进来的。
- We're overlooking his obvious flaws
- 我们在忽视他明显的缺点
and vile family because he's a great singer.
- 和他那讨厌的家庭，因为他是个出色的歌手。
- Yeah, we'll definitely raise enough money
- 是的，我们肯定能筹到足够的钱
to impress those girls.
- 来打动那些女孩。
And help that duck. - Duck?
- 还能帮助那只鸭子。 - 鸭子？
- Goose. both: Right.
- 鹅。 都对。
- It's all about the goose, isn't it, Joey?
- 一切都是为了那只鹅，对吧，Joey？
- Yeah.
- 是啊。
Sometimes I think could get lost in the goose's eyes forever.
有时候我觉得我可以永远迷失在那只鹅的眼睛里。
- It's a goose, dude. Take it down a notch.
- 那只是一只鹅，伙计。冷静点。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- I think you're the goose.
- 我觉得你才是那只鹅。
- I know.
- 我知道。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Look, I don't care how you feel about that goose--
听着，我不在乎你对那只鹅有什么感觉——
who feels the same way about you,
它对你的感觉也是一样的，
but this is a terrible idea.
但这是个糟糕的主意。
- [gasps] Montagelli.
蒙塔格利。
- Dad, the boys want this Montagelli
爸，孩子们想要蒙塔格利
to play the benefit. - No.
来演奏慈善音乐会。不行。
A Montagelli has no business being in our store.
蒙塔格利家的人没资格进我们店。
- Ugh, come on. Joey's voice is so good,
哎，拜托。乔伊的嗓音那么好，
it'll raise tons of money for Charity.
能为慈善筹集很多钱。
- Yeah, you just need to hear him play.
对，你只需要听听他演奏。
- ♪ And if you feel you're sinking ♪
如果你感觉在下沉
♪ I will jump right over ♪
我会立刻跳过去
♪ Into cold, cold water for you ♪
♪ 为你跳进冰冷的水中 ♪
♪ And although time... ♪
♪ 尽管时间... ♪
- I can't believe that beautiful voice
我真不敢相信这么美的声音
is coming out of a Montagelli.
是从一台Montagelli钢琴里传出来的。
- So he can play at the benefit?
那他能在慈善活动上演奏吗？
- ♪ You ♪ - Yes.
♪ 你 ♪ - 是的。
- Yes! - Ah.
是的！ - 啊。
- He's a revelation.
他真是个惊喜。
[playing "Cold Water"]
[演奏《冷冷水》]
- ♪ I'll be your lifeline... ♪
♪ 我会是你的救生索... ♪
- Why does the guy who likes me so much
- 为什么那个这么喜欢我的家伙
have to be so good-looking and talented?
又帅又有才呢？
- Yeah, it's a real tragedy.
- 是啊，真是个悲剧。
- This guy's good. - Very good.
- 这家伙不错。 - 非常不错。
- There's nothing better than a boy with a beautiful voice.
- 没有什么比一个拥有美妙嗓音的男孩更棒的了。
- Maybe too good.
- 可能太好了。
- We don't stand a chance with the girls
- 如果我们不把女孩们从那个金嗓子歌鸟身边引开，
if we don't get 'em away from that golden-throated songbird.
我们就没有机会了。
- But that golden-throated songbird
- 但那个金嗓子歌鸟
is our only way to have a chance with the girls.
是我们唯一有机会接近女孩们的途径。
♪ ♪
- ♪ I'll be your lifeline tonight ♪
♪ 我今晚将成为你的生命线 ♪
♪ I won't let go ♪
♪ 我不会放手 ♪
[applause]
[掌声]
Thank you, guys, for letting me play the benefit.
谢谢大家，让我有机会参与这次慈善演出。
I probably should go before my parents notice.
我可能应该在父母发现之前离开。
- Bye, Joey.
再见，Joey。
[together] Bye, Joey.
- We've made a terrible miscalculation.
我们犯了一个严重的错误。
- Maybe we should forget about the girls
也许我们应该放弃追求女孩
and do this for Charity.
我们或许应该为慈善做这件事。
[all laugh]
[大家一起笑]
- Joey's gotta go.
- Joey得走了。
♪♪
- Oh, good, you got my text. Look, I just wanted to talk
- 哦，太好了，你收到了我的短信。看，我只是想和你谈谈
to you about what's goin-- - Joey, I get it.
关于正在发生的事情-- - Joey，我明白了。
I know how you feel about the goose,
我知道你对那只鹅的感觉，
but you playing in the store's too risky.
但你在店里演奏太冒险了。
We could get caught.
我们可能会被抓到。
But what do you think? - Well, I mean--
但你怎么看？ - 嗯，我是说--
- I hear you. This way we could
我明白你的意思。这样我们可以
spend more time together, which would be nice, I know.
花更多时间在一起，这很好，我知道。
But is it to dangerous? - I think that--
但这是不是太危险了？我觉得——
- You're right. It's gonna be too hard
你说得对。假装什么都没发生
to act like there's nothing going on.
太难了。
Look, especially when you keep giving me those goo-goo eyes.
看，特别是你一直对我投以那种含情脉脉的眼神。
But I love the goo-goo eyes.
但我喜欢那种含情脉脉的眼神。
Don't stop giving me the goo-goo eyes.
别停止给我那种眼神。
Ugh, enough with the goo-goo eyes.
唉，够了，那种眼神。
Maybe we should just let everyone know
也许我们应该让所有人知道
that we like each other? Do you think that
我们喜欢对方吗？你觉得
would change their minds? - I mean, it couldn't--
那会改变他们的想法吗？ - 我的意思是，它不可能--
- I know. It'll be impossible
- 我知道。那是不可能的
because the Harpers and Montagellis
因为Harpers和Montagellis
will never understand. You're right.
永远不会理解。你说得对。
- Look, Dawn-- - Then it's agreed.
- 看，Dawn-- - 那么就这么定了。
- We'll do the event and we'll keep us a secret.
- 我们会办这个活动，并且保持我们的秘密。
Yes? Okay.
是吗？好的。
Thank you so much for helping me figure this out.
非常感谢你帮我理清这一切。
You always know exactly what to say.
你总是知道该说什么。
- [sighs] You know what, Charity?
- [叹气] 你知道吗，Charity？
I really like-- [goose honks]
我真的很喜欢-- [鹅叫声]
You too? Ow.
你也是？哎哟。
- That Joey's so cute.
- 那个Joey真可爱。
- I wish I were a goose without a gaggle.
- 我真希望自己是一只没有群的鹅。
- It's still warm.
- 还是暖和的。
- You'd think a guy that good-looking and that talented
- 你会以为一个长得那么帅又有才华的人
would already have a girl and wouldn't have to steal ours.
早就应该有女朋友了，不需要抢我们的。
- Yeah, how is a hunk like that not taken?
- 是啊，像他那样的帅哥怎么还没被追走？
- Taken. That's it.
- 追走。就是这个词。
Boy, that Joey.
真是个 Joey。
What a dreamboat.
简直是梦中情人。
Too bad he's taken. - What?
可惜他已经名花有主了。- 什么？
- No. - Who is she?
- 没有。- 她是谁？
- Uh, who is she?
- 她是谁？
She's, uh...
呃，她是...
Dawn.
Dawn。
- What? - I had no idea.
- 什么？- 我完全不知道。
- Lucky. - Sorry, ladies.
- 真幸运。- 对不起，女士们。
His FaceShack status says his shack door's closed.
他的FaceShack状态显示他的小屋大门已经关闭了。
- The seat is cold.
座位是凉的。
- Nice lie, Dicky.
不错的谎言，迪基。
- Yeah, that solved everything. - And best of all,
是啊，那解决了所有问题。
caused absolutely no problems. - [laughs]
而且最棒的是，
- Dawn, we have a problem. - What's wrong?
没有引起任何问题。
- Faith, Hope, and Susan were just in my store
道恩，我们有问题了。
talking about how bummed they are that
怎么了？
you and I are hanging out.
信念、希望和苏珊刚在我的店里
I thought we agreed that we weren't gonna tell anyone.
谈论他们对我们俩在一起有多失望。
- We did. - Well, I didn't tell anybody.
我以为我们说好了不告诉任何人。
Did you? - Of course not.
你呢？ - 当然没有。
I would never tell-- oh, no.
我绝不会告诉——哦，不。
- What?
- 什么？
- How could you do this to us?
- 你怎么能这样对我们？
My mom and dad overheard and grounded me,
我爸妈无意中听到了，把我关在家里，
and now I can't leave the store.
现在我不能离开商店。
I mean, I hate to say it,
我是说，虽然不愿意这么说，
but I guess this is good-bye, Dawn.
但我想这可能是我们最后一次见面了，Dawn。
- Wait, Joey, no, I-- [dial tone hums]
- 等等，Joey，不，我——[拨号音嗡嗡作响]
Mae, what did you do?
Mae，你做了什么？
- You said I could have pie. - No, with Joey.
- 你说我可以吃派的。 - 不，是和Joey。
You told Faith, Hope, and Susan about us.
你告诉了Faith、Hope和Susan我们的事。
- I did not.
- 我没有。
- Well, then if you didn't, who did?
- 那如果不是你，会是谁？
- I don't know.
- 我不知道。
why don't you just ask the girls?
你为什么不直接问那几个女孩？
- You jerks. - Duck.
- 你们这些混蛋。 - 鸭子。
- Duck. - Goose.
- 鸭子。 - 鹅。
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
Oh, I get it. Duck.
哦，我明白了。鸭子。
[rock music]
- Look, I don't know how you blabber mouths found out,
- 听着，我不知道你们这些大嘴巴是怎么打听到的，
but because of your loose lips, Joey just broke up with me.
但是因为你们的口无遮拦，乔伊刚刚和我分手了。
- Dawn, Dawn, Dawn.
- 黎明，黎明，黎明。
Joey's not your boyfriend.
乔伊不是你的男朋友。
That was a lie we made up
那只是我们编造的谎言
to keep the girls from falling for him.
为了不让那些女孩们爱上他。
- Yeah, if you haven't noticed, he's quite the catch.
- 是啊，如果你还没注意到，他可是个抢手货。
- I know! He was my catch!
- 我知道！他本该是我的猎物！
I caught him!
我抓住他了！
We were just keeping it a secret so our feuding families
我们只是保密，以免我们争吵的家庭
wouldn't break us up.
不会把我们拆散。
[together] Oh.
[一起] 哦。
- How could you lie about me like that?
- 你怎么能那样说我？
- Well, in our defense, it turned out to be true.
- 好吧，在我们辩护一下，结果证明是真的。
So, technically, not a lie.
所以，严格来说，不是谎言。
- Hey, at least you'll see him at the benefit.
- 嘿，至少你会在慈善活动上见到他。
- He's not doing the benefit. He's grounded.
- 他不参加慈善活动。他被禁足了。
- Great. Now this is affecting us.
- 太好了。现在这影响到了我们。
- Mae, get more pie.
- 梅，再拿些派。
- [muffled] I ate it all.
- [含糊不清] 我全吃光了。
- Let us fix this.
- 让我们来解决这个问题。
We'll explain to Joey what happened
我们会向Joey解释发生了什么
and I'm sure he'll forgive you.
而且我确信他会原谅你的。
- No. No fixing, no nothing.
- 不。不需要解决，什么都不需要。
Stay. Outta. My. Business!
别管我的事！
- Hey. Why'd I get poked twice?
- 嘿。为什么我被戳了两次？
- Yeah, thanks a lot, Nicky. - Hey.
- 是啊，非常感谢，Nicky。 - 嘿。
[both grumbling]
[两人都在咕哝]
- Stop it.
- 停下。
Look, I know Dawn just said
听着，我知道Dawn刚刚说
to stay out of her business, but we've got to speak to Joey
让我们别管她的事，但我们得找Joey
and fix things. Otherwise we've got no show.
解决问题。不然我们就没有节目了。
- Yeah, and no girls.
- 是啊，也没有女孩们。
- The Montagellis banned us.
- Montagellis家族禁止我们了。
How are we gonna get into the groomers?
我们怎么进得去美容院？
- [stomach rumbling]
- [肚子咕噜响]
- Hey, I told you not to eat the egg salad.
- 嘿，我告诉过你别吃那鸡蛋沙拉。
- Yeah, the egg salad was fine.
- 是啊，鸡蛋沙拉没问题。
It was the verge. - Hey!
问题出在边缘。 - 嘿！
- Don't poke him.
He could explode.
♪ ♪
[door chimes]
- [grunts]
Steady down there.
- You guys are heavy.
- Well, it's not picnic being the meat
in this dumdum sandwich, either.
- Shh.
- Is everything okay?
- 一切都好吗？
- [imitating adult voice] Yes, everything's good for me.
- [模仿成人声音] 是的，对我来说一切都好。
Gerald T. Honeycutt. [chuckles awkwardly]
杰拉尔德·T·汉尼卡特。[尴尬地笑]
"T" stands for "Tall."
“T”代表“高”。
Ah, there's my destination,
啊，那是我的目的地，
the grooming counter.
美容柜台。
Just four steps forward.
只需向前走四步。
[shakily] Two, three...
[颤抖地] 二，三...
and four.
和四。
Okay, maybe two big steps to my right.
好的，也许向右迈两大步。
Yep. Nope.
是的。不。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Okay, maybe one not so big step to my left.
好吧，也许向左迈一小步。
Okay, one tiny step forward.
好的，向前迈一小步。
Tinier!
更小！
Hello, young man.
你好，年轻人。
Would you groom my cat, Scrunchie?
你能给我的猫Scrunchie美容吗？
Psst, psst.
嘘，嘘。
[whispering forcefully] This isn't really a cat,
[用力低语] 这其实不是一只猫，
and I'm not really a man.
而我也不是真的一个男人。
It's Nicky.
这是尼基。
- And Ricky.
- 和瑞奇。
- And Dicky.
- 和迪基。
- Yeah, no kidding.
- 对，没开玩笑。
- We're here to apologize.
我们是来道歉的。
We're the ones who accidentally spilled beans
是我们不小心泄露了你和道恩的事。
about you and Dawn. - It was you?
- 是你们？
It wasn't Dawn's fault? - Nope.
不是道恩的错？
So you'll perform at the benefit, right?
那你会在慈善演出上表演吧？
- I can't. I'm grounded.
- 我不能，我被禁足了。
[door chimes] - [giggles]
[门铃声] - [咯咯笑]
- Someone's coming.
- 有人来了。
- [falsetto] Excuse me.
- [假声] 打扰一下。
[imitating southern accent] My name's Penelope V. Tall.
[模仿南方口音] 我叫佩内洛普·V·塔尔。
[giggling] The "V" stands for "Very."
[咯咯笑] 那个“V”代表“非常”。
I was just wondering if I could get some French tips
我想知道我能不能给我的猫咪的脚趾甲做些法式美甲。她真的很讲究。
for my kitty's toenails. She's real fancy.
- 哦，不，Dawn来了。
- Oh, no, Dawn's here.
- Dawn来了？
- Dawn's here?
- [正常声音] 你们在这里做什么？
- [normal voice] What are you guys doing here?
- 男孩们在这里？ - 在哪里？
- The boys are here? - Where?
男孩们在这里？ - 在哪里？
- They told me what happened. I'm sorry I accused you, Dawn.
他们告诉我发生了什么。我很抱歉我指责了你，Dawn。
- That's okay. I forgive you.
没关系。我原谅你。
but I don't forgive you.
但我不会原谅你。
I told you to stay out of my business.
我告诉过你不要插手我的事。
- Hey!
嘿！
No one pokes Gerald T. Honeycutt.
没人能惹Gerald T. Honeycutt。
- Ow. Stop it.
哎哟。停下来。
- Hey, no fighting in our store.
嘿，不要在我们店里打架。
- Ah!
啊！
- Harpers?
哈珀家的人？
What're you doing here?
你们来这儿干什么？
- Look, they were explaining themselves.
听着，他们是在解释自己。
Can we just calm down and forget about his stupid feud?
我们能不能冷静下来，忘掉他们之间的愚蠢争执？
- No way.
没门。
The Harpers are bad people.
哈珀家的人不是好人。
Now take your long coats and get out.
你们带着长外套赶紧走吧。
- Come on, Dawn. - No.
拜托了，道恩。
Just like always, you meddled,
不行。
you didn't respect me, and you ruined everything.
和往常一样，你们多管闲事，不尊重我，把一切都搞砸了。
- Dawn, we're sorry, but you ca--
- 道恩，我们很抱歉，但你不能--
- No, I'm not going.
- 不，我不会走的。
I'd rather be a Montagelli than a Harper.
我宁愿成为蒙塔格利家的人，也不愿是哈珀家的。
[both gasp]
[两人同时吸气]
- Let's go.
- 我们走吧。
♪ ♪
- So what're you gonna tell your parents?
- 那你打算怎么跟你父母说？
- Can we just forget about my family for a moment?
- 我们能不能暂时不提我的家人？
- That's gonna be kind of difficult.
- 那会有点困难。
- Why? - Because they're right there.
- 为什么？ - 因为他们就在那里。
- Wait. What are you guys doing?
等等，你们在干什么？
- Just listen.
就听着。
Hit it, Dooley.
开始吧，杜利。
[off-key] ♪ There's a goose out here alone ♪
这里有一只孤零零的鹅
♪ And they miss her a lot back home ♪
她在家里很想念她
♪ They're gaggle doesn't fly the same without her ♪
没有她，她们的队伍飞得不再一样
- [off-key] ♪ And we know how much that hurts ♪
我们知道那有多伤人
♪ Our sister left 'cause we're the worst ♪
我们的姐姐离开了，因为我们是最差的
♪ And that's why we wrote this awesome song
这就是为什么我们写了这首很棒的歌
♪ About her... ♪
关于她的...
- Yeah, I wouldn't call it "awesome."
是的，我不会称之为“棒极了”。
- [off-key] ♪ Help this bird go home ♪
[走调地唱] ♪ 帮助这只鸟儿回家 ♪
[piano music]
[钢琴音乐]
♪ Donate money with your phone ♪
♪ 用你的手机捐款 ♪
♪ And maybe Dawn will forgive us ♪
♪ 也许Dawn会原谅我们 ♪
♪ And understand that we didn't mean to hurt her feelings ♪
♪ 并理解我们并非有意伤害她的感情 ♪
♪ And we like her-- ♪ - Hey, guys, guys, guys!
♪ 我们喜欢她—— ♪ - 嘿，伙计们，伙计们，伙计们！
Stop.
停。
That was really...
那真的很...
terrible.
糟糕。
- But we're still posting it online
但是我们还是把它上传到网上了
so everybody can see
这样每个人都能看到
how terrible and embarrassing we are.
我们有多糟糕和尴尬。
- Including Faith, Hope, and Susan.
包括Faith、Hope和Susan。
- You'd do all that for Charity, huh?
你这样做是为了Charity，是吗？
- No.
不。
We'd do it for our sister.
我们这样做是为了我们的妹妹。
- Can you forgive us and come back home?
你能原谅我们并回家吗？
- I mean, they were willing to embarrass themselves
我的意思是，他们愿意为了补偿你而让自己出丑。
pretty hardcore to make it up to you.
相当卖力地。
- Yeah. This is terrible.
是啊，这太糟糕了。
- Maybe it's not so bad to be a Harper after all.
也许成为哈珀家的人也没那么糟糕。
- Dawn?
Dawn？
Why are you holding hands with a-a Montagelli?
你为什么要和一个蒙塔格利家的人牵手？
- Maybe because she wised up
也许是因为她醒悟了
and doesn't wanna be a stinking Harper anymore.
不想再当一个臭名昭著的哈珀家的人了。
[all talking at once] - Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
别吵了，别吵了，别吵了，别吵了。
No more feuding.
不要再争斗了。
Dawn and Joey like each other, okay?
Dawn和Joey互相喜欢，好吗？
- Wh--Dawn, is that true?
什么？Dawn，这是真的吗？
- That should be more important than any childish feud.
- 这应该比任何孩子气的争执都更重要。
- Yeah, you're all adults,
- 是的，你们都是成年人，
and you should start acting like it.
- 你们应该开始表现得像成年人。
- Yeah, well, he started it. - Okay, Tom.
- 是啊，是他先挑起的。 - 好吧，汤姆。
The boys are right.
- 男孩们说得对。
For the kids' sake, we need to call a truce.
- 为了孩子们，我们需要宣布停战。
Agreed?
- 同意吗？
- Agreed. - Okay.
- 同意。 - 好的。
- Tom? - [exhales]
- 汤姆？ - [叹气]
Fine. For the kids.
- 好吧。为了孩子们。
- Yes. Thank you, Mom and Dad.
是的。谢谢爸爸妈妈。
- So, would you guys like to come in for some egg salad?
那么，你们想进来吃点鸡蛋沙拉吗？
- Okay, Tom, no. [goose honking]
好吧，汤姆，不了。
- Huh, she could fly.
哈，她能飞。
- I guess she didn't wanna hear Dicky sing again.
我猜她不想再听迪基唱歌了。
- I'm gonna miss that crazy duck.
我会想念那只疯狂的鸭子。
- Duck? [bird screeches]
鸭子？
all: Eagle!
老鹰！
[rock music]
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
♪ ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪